# 大家好 今天天氣好冷哦
Hi everyone! It's freezing today.
# 我去看一下兄弟家的甘蔗有沒有砍完
I'm gonna have a look at my buddy's sugar canes and see if there are any left.
# 上次看到他開了幾輪拖頭(車)在那裡哦
Last time I saw him with several trucks over there.
# 不知道有沒有沒砍掉的
I wonder if there are any left.
# 鴨子
Duckies!
# 小鴨子
Little duckies!
# 你看兄弟家的大棚 裡面還有好多哦
Look! These are my buddy's sheds. There are still a lot inside.
# 這邊就已經砍完啦
Those on this side have already been chopped.
# 你看 那麼多甘蔗都不砍 放在這裡好多哇
Look! Here are so many sugar canes. My buddy didn't chop them.
# 我找一根 找一根最小的來
Let me get a, get a smallest one,
# 嘗一下
and have a try.
# 這根
This one!
# 這根長得不好看
This one doesn't look good.
# 最小
It's the smallest.
# 剛好帶了一把刀過來
I happen to have a knife with me,
# 我家的菜刀
my kitchen knife.
# 哎呀
Aya!
# 這甘蔗就好吃啦 這種甘蔗
This sugar cane is really tasty, you know.
# 味道肯定很好
A good taste is ensured.
# 哎呀 好重 這根甘蔗差不多10斤哦
Aya! So heavy! This sugar cane is almost five kilograms.
# 那麼重
It's so heavy!
# 這甘蔗
This sugar cane...
# 嘗一下 看味道怎麼樣
Let me have a try, and see how it tastes.
# 你看 這個結頭那麼多 肯定不靚哦
Look! There are so many buds. It can't grow beautifully.
# 幫兄弟 幫兄弟吃掉 這結得太多啦
Let me get rid of it, get rid of it for my buddy. There are too many buds.
# 你看 削好啦
Look! It's alright now.
# 嗯 可以
Um! Not bad!
# 這個味道可以
It's a good taste.
# 不過有點硬
But it's a bit hard.
# 我帶回家裡去吃
I bring it back home.
# 來都來啦 搞一根
I'm already here. How can I just take one?
# 搞兩根來 好事要成雙
Let me get two. Good things should come in pairs.
# 你看 這根比較小
Look! This one is rather small.
# 這根砍啦
I'll take it.
# 拿著
Hold it!
# 要不要吃 可以吃一點
Do you want it? You can have some.
# 好啦 好啦 不要啦 我都背不起啦
Alright, alright! Enough! It's already too heavy for me.
# 現在我們回去啦
We're heading back now.
# 刀又沒帶
I left my knife at home.
# 這香蕉
The bananas,
# 很靚的哦
are really beautiful!
# 可以不是很大
Though they're not that big.
# 把它砍回去
Let me take it back home.
# 你看 這個香蕉樹都死掉啦
Look! This banana tree is already dead.
# 我把這個香蕉帶回家裡去
I'm gonna take the bananas home.
# 太小啦
They're too small.
# 反正都死啦 我拿那個
It's dead anyway. Let me,
# 用鋤頭把它搞一來
take it down with a hoe.
# 這個鋤頭把它鏟下來
I'll chop it down with this hoe.
# 這個搞不開
I can't break it here.
# 我回去拿刀
Let me fetch a knife.
# 回去拿一把刀過來
Let me fetch a knife first.
# 搞這樣了 搞不下
It's impossible otherwise.
# 帶了一把刀過來 沒找到小刀 就找到這把 (註︰這把也不大，我想他的「小刀」是指水果刀之類的吧)
So I'm back with a knife. I can't find a paring knife, only this one.
# 這個刀
This knife,
# 就把你卸(註︰應該是「切」)下來
is enough to cut you off.
# 很鋒利呀
It's really sharp!
# 哎呦
Ayo!
# 香蕉都被切走一半
Half of the banana is cut away.
# 我把它抬回家 放在那裡 看會不會熟
I'll bring it back home, put it there and see if it will ripen.